<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 16.05.2022 - 22.05.2022 (Этап 5)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of labs beforehand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned to work in the emacs editor. Studied the basics of programming in the UNIX/Linux OS shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned to write small batch files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned to write more complex batch files using logical control structures and cycles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu2911a1e140c08098424f827f76406561_98783_6c93a2bdfadc5629be5f5c279e6fc7e1.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu2911a1e140c08098424f827f76406561_98783_6fcef1222ff2cc0f5b9e1f98b504d741.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu2911a1e140c08098424f827f76406561_98783_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu2911a1e140c08098424f827f76406561_98783_6c93a2bdfadc5629be5f5c279e6fc7e1.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;521&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also wrote a paper on &amp;ldquo;Network topology&amp;rdquo;. This is quite an interesting topic to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/2_huc5557d7784d054b5475a772a7f6eaebb_63151_ac4a79783ea8dfa04d7cb7221883f282.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/2_huc5557d7784d054b5475a772a7f6eaebb_63151_ef7302079f01c12c9a0a648d589f61bd.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/2_huc5557d7784d054b5475a772a7f6eaebb_63151_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/2_huc5557d7784d054b5475a772a7f6eaebb_63151_ac4a79783ea8dfa04d7cb7221883f282.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;709&#34;
               height=&#34;721&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A novice data scientist has the opportunity to choose from a variety of programming languages ​​that will help him master this science faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, no one can tell you exactly which programming language is best suited for this purpose. Your success as a specialist in this field will depend on many factors, and today we will try to consider them, and at the end of the article you can vote for the programming language that you consider the most suitable for working with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;specificity&#34;&gt;Specificity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared for the fact that as you delve deeper into the field of data science, you will have to “reinvent the wheel” over and over again. In addition, you will need to become fluent in various software packages and modules for your chosen programming language. How well you can learn all this depends, first of all, on the availability of domain-specific software packages for the selected programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;versatility&#34;&gt;Versatility&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lead Data Scientist has good all-round programming skills, as well as the ability to perform calculations and analyzes. Much of the day-to-day work in data science is focused on finding and processing original data or correcting data. Unfortunately, no new machine learning packages will help you for these purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;efficiency&#34;&gt;Efficiency&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced world of commercial data science, there are plenty of opportunities to get the job you want quickly. However, it is precisely because of the rapid development of the field of data science that technical shortcomings constantly accompany it, and only persistent practice can minimize such shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, it is very important to optimize the performance of your code, especially when dealing with large amounts of critical data. However, compiled languages ​​are usually much faster than interpreted ones. Similarly, statically typed languages ​​are significantly more fault tolerant than dynamically typed ones. So the only tradeoff is performance degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent, each of the programming languages ​​below has one parameter in each of two groups: universality - specificity; performance is convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these basic principles in mind, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at some of the more popular programming languages ​​that are used in data science. All information about the programming languages ​​below is based on my own observations and experience, as well as the experience of my friends and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu232eb44fcb8648da2b10aac7471ced95_573388_71c41002f9452442a1accee17d2fa3bb.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu232eb44fcb8648da2b10aac7471ced95_573388_e7a152b032d4d4a5bdc3a3b46e741882.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu232eb44fcb8648da2b10aac7471ced95_573388_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu232eb44fcb8648da2b10aac7471ced95_573388_71c41002f9452442a1accee17d2fa3bb.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;589&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R, which is a direct descendant of the older programming language S, was released back in 1995 and has been getting better ever since. Written in languages ​​such as C and Fortran, this project is now supported by the R Foundation for Statistical Computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An excellent set of high quality open source domain-specific packages. R has packages at its disposal for just about every quantitative and statistical application imaginable. This includes neural networks, non-linear regression, phylogenetics, building complex diagrams, graphs, and much, much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with the basic installation in the appendage, we are given the opportunity to install extensive built-in functions and methods. Also, R handles matrix algebra data nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to visualize data is an important advantage, along with the ability to use various libraries, such as ggplot2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low performance. Nothing to say here: R is not a fast language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specificity. R is great for statistical research and data science, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as good when it comes to programming for general purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other features. R has several unusual features that can confuse programmers used to working with other languages: indexing starts at 1, multiple assignment operators, non-traditional data structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is ideal for initial purposes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R is a powerful language that has a huge selection of data collection and data visualization applications, and the fact that it is an open source language allows it to garner a large following among developers. It was because of its effectiveness for the original purposes that this programming language managed to achieve wide popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hueadeedd0aefea7f5be3157349013bfad_20579_c1fa704d2e35c30333880c57ada1229f.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hueadeedd0aefea7f5be3157349013bfad_20579_a7853f3024463eb1f0894a92907366aa.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hueadeedd0aefea7f5be3157349013bfad_20579_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hueadeedd0aefea7f5be3157349013bfad_20579_c1fa704d2e35c30333880c57ada1229f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;330&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1991, Guido van Rossum introduced the Python programming language. Since then, the language has become a hugely popular general-purpose language and is widely used in the data science community. Currently, the main versions are Python 3.6 and Python 2.7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python is a very popular, widely used general purpose programming language. It has an extensive set of specially designed modules and is widely used by developers. Many online services provide an API for Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python is very easy to learn. The low barrier to entry makes it an ideal first language for those who are into programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software packages such as pandas, scikit-learn, and Tensorflow make Python a solid choice for modern machine learning applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type safety. Python is a dynamically typed language, which means you have to be careful when working with it. Type mismatch errors (such as passing a string as an argument to a method that expects an integer) can happen from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, if there are specific goals for statistical analysis and data analysis, then the extensive set of packages of the R language gives it an advantage over Python. In addition, there are faster and safer alternatives to Python among programming languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict - Easy to&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use Python is a good choice for data science purposes, and this statement holds true for both beginner and advanced levels of work in the field. Much of data science is centered around the ETL (extract-transform-load) process. This feature makes Python an ideal programming language for such purposes. Libraries like Google&amp;rsquo;s Tensorflow make Python a very interesting language to work in the field of machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SQL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;4&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/4_huc69a800cdc07053622cec109bf871667_11756_01a1f66039ba6a068b7b0e8e51656d52.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/4_huc69a800cdc07053622cec109bf871667_11756_914447ec6ca8dc3b7cccbffb21020d45.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/4_huc69a800cdc07053622cec109bf871667_11756_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/4_huc69a800cdc07053622cec109bf871667_11756_01a1f66039ba6a068b7b0e8e51656d52.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;600&#34;
               height=&#34;315&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQL (&amp;ldquo;Structured Query Language&amp;rdquo;) defines, manages and queries relational databases. The language appeared in 1974 and since then has undergone many modifications, but its basic principles remain unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are free and paid options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is very effective when working with queries, updates, as well as when processing relational databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The declarative syntax makes SQL a very readable language. There is no ambiguity about what SELECT name FROM users WHERE age &amp;gt; 18 should do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL is used very often in various applications, so getting to know it can be very useful. Modules like SQLAlchemy make it easy to integrate SQL with other languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL syntax can seem like a pretty daunting task for those used to imperative programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many different variations of SQL such as PostgreSQL, SQLite, MariaDB. All of them are quite different, so there can be no question of any compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is efficient despite the time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQL is more useful as a data processing language than as an advanced analytics tool. However, so many data science processes depend on ETL, and the longevity and efficiency of SQL is yet another proof that every data scientist should know such a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;java&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;5&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/5_hu2c0e77e28a13c324b6c194306a34447b_25531_1390fdd6222c16cbb7177881df6d097d.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/5_hu2c0e77e28a13c324b6c194306a34447b_25531_ca0397f67a1fd40adacbb656b543a8cd.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/5_hu2c0e77e28a13c324b6c194306a34447b_25531_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/5_hu2c0e77e28a13c324b6c194306a34447b_25531_1390fdd6222c16cbb7177881df6d097d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;399&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java is an extremely popular general purpose language that runs on the Java Virtual Machine (JVM). It is an abstract computing system that allows for seamless portability across platforms. Currently supported by Oracle Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8th version - free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versatility. Many modern systems and applications are developed using the Java language. A huge advantage of such a PL is the ability to integrate data science methods directly into the existing code base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strict typing. Type safety is not an empty phrase for Java, and in the case of developing mission-critical applications for working with big data, this feature is more important than ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java is a high performance, general purpose compiled language. This makes it suitable for writing efficient production ETL code as well as machine learning algorithms using computational tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The verbosity of the Java language makes it not a good choice for ad hoc analyzes and the development of more specialized statistical applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java does not have many libraries for advanced statistical methods compared to some domain-specific languages ​​such as R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is a serious contender for the best language for data science work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to be said for learning Java as a language for data science work. Many companies will appreciate the ability to seamlessly integrate the finished product code into their own code base, and the performance and type safety of Java are its undeniable advantages. However, the disadvantages of such a language include the fact that it does not have a set of specific packages that are available for other languages. Despite this shortcoming, Java is a programming language that you should definitely pay attention to, especially if you already know R or Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scala&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scala&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;6&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/6_hu679d4a3d9fe32b65a50142d67d4ac95c_8603_ab24d65411b7ce5fb59e6a2e4984620d.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/6_hu679d4a3d9fe32b65a50142d67d4ac95c_8603_3df4b524bcb153187755e7fa884f5ba7.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/6_hu679d4a3d9fe32b65a50142d67d4ac95c_8603_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/6_hu679d4a3d9fe32b65a50142d67d4ac95c_8603_ab24d65411b7ce5fb59e6a2e4984620d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;635&#34;
               height=&#34;282&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JVM-based Scala programming language was developed by Martin Odersky in 2004. It is a multi-paradigm language that allows for both object-oriented and functional approaches. In addition, the Apache Spark cluster computing framework is written in Scala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Scala and Spark, you have the opportunity to work with high-performance cluster computing. Scala is the perfect choice for those who work with large amounts of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiparadigmatic. For Scala programmers, both object-oriented and functional programming paradigms are available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala compiles to Java bytecode and runs on the JVM. This allows it to interoperate with the Java language, making Scala a very powerful general purpose language. In addition, it is also well suited for data science jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are just going to work with Scala, then be prepared to pretty &amp;ldquo;break&amp;rdquo; your head. Your best bet is to download sbt and set up an IDE like Eclipse or IntelliJ with a dedicated Scala plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is an opinion that Scala&amp;rsquo;s syntax and type system are quite complex. Thus, programmers who are accustomed to working with dynamic languages ​​such as Python will have a hard time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is ideal for working with big data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide to use cluster computing for working with big data, then Scala + Spark is the perfect solution. Moreover, if you already have experience with Java and other statically typed programming languages, then you will certainly appreciate these features of Scala. However, if your application doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with large amounts of data that would justify adding all the Scala pieces, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely get better performance using other languages ​​like R or Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;julia&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;7&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/7_hu3374812572387c796995fbe5f5d38c5c_43090_70bac215df425772976d39c9f925d8ec.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/7_hu3374812572387c796995fbe5f5d38c5c_43090_afffe177ce428a0ed0b2421989c06069.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/7_hu3374812572387c796995fbe5f5d38c5c_43090_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/7_hu3374812572387c796995fbe5f5d38c5c_43090_70bac215df425772976d39c9f925d8ec.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;514&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released just over 5 years ago, Julia made an impression on the world of computational methods. The language gained such popularity because several large organizations, including some in the financial industry, began using it for their own purposes almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia is a JIT (just in time) compiled language that achieves good performance. This language is quite simple, it provides for the dynamic typing and scripting capabilities of an interpreted language such as Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia was intended for numerical analysis, it can also be considered as a general purpose programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readability. Many programmers who work with the language consider this feature to be its greatest advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immaturity. Since Julia is a fairly new language, some developers experience instability while working with its packages. However, the core features of the language are considered stable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another sign of the immaturity of the language is the limited number of software packages, as well as a small number of fans among developers. Unlike the established R and Python, the Julia programming language does not have a large number of software packages (yet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict - a language that will show itself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the main problem of the Julia language is its youth, but you can&amp;rsquo;t blame it for that. Since Julia was only recently created, it cannot yet compete with its main competitors, Python and R. Be patient and you will find that there are many reasons to pay close attention to this language, which is sure to make outstanding strides in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;matlab&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MATLAB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;8&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/8_hu59c4fbe749e0880d8c64686d514c1955_62343_c49eb4d6125f28a8a1c4242df81c2bac.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/8_hu59c4fbe749e0880d8c64686d514c1955_62343_c14b848557400c2fae5a7b81af1ef99e.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/8_hu59c4fbe749e0880d8c64686d514c1955_62343_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/8_hu59c4fbe749e0880d8c64686d514c1955_62343_c49eb4d6125f28a8a1c4242df81c2bac.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;498&#34;
               height=&#34;500&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MATLAB is a recognized language for numerical calculations, used both for scientific purposes and in industry. It was developed and licensed by MathWorks, a company founded in 1984 with the primary goal of commercializing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;License:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prices vary depending on the language option you choose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MATLAB, designed for numerical computing, is well suited for using quantitative analysis with complex mathematical requirements such as signal processing, Fourier transforms, matrix algebra, and image processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data visualization. MATLAB has a number of built-in plotting and charting capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MATLAB is often found in many undergraduate courses in the exact sciences, such as physics, engineering, and applied mathematics. Therefore, it is widely used in these areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid license. Regardless of the option you choose (for scientific, personal or company purposes), you will have to fork out for an expensive license. Our advice: check out the free alternative - Octave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MATLAB is not the best general purpose programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is the best option for purposes that require significant mathematical calculations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to its wide use in various quantitative calculations for both scientific and industrial purposes, MATLAB has become a worthy option for data science applications. It will come in very handy if your daily goals require intensive, advanced mathematical functionality, in fact, for which MATLAB was designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-languages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other languages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other popular PLs that may be of interest to data scientists. This section provides a brief overview of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, C++ is not used in the field of data science. However, it has lightning-fast performance and wide popularity. The main reason why C++ has not gained popularity in the field of data science is its inefficiency for such a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one forum member wrote:
“Suppose you are writing code to do some kind of custom analysis that will probably run only once. Now, would you rather spend 30 minutes creating a program that will run for 10 seconds or spend 10 minutes making a program that will run for 1 minute?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this guy is right! However, C++ would be an excellent choice for implementing low-level optimized machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is not the best choice for daily work, but when it comes to performance&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Node.js platform has evolved over the past few years, the JavaScript programming language has become more and more of a server-side language. However, its capabilities in the field of data science and machine learning are rather modest today (still, don&amp;rsquo;t forget about brain.js and synaptic.js!). The disadvantages of JavaScript include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too early for it to come into play (Node.js is only 8 years old!)&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Node.js platform is really fast, but there will always be those who will actively criticize JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undeniable advantages of Node.js include its asynchronous I/O, its growing popularity, and the fact that there are many languages ​​that compile with JavaScript. So it is quite possible that in the near future we will see a useful framework for data science work with the ability to process using ETL in real time. Another question: will it be relevant at that time &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict - there is still a lot of work to be done in order for JavaScript to be considered a worthy language for working in the field of data science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;perl&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perl is known as the &amp;ldquo;Swiss army knife of programming languages&amp;rdquo; because of its versatility as a general-purpose scripting language. It shares many similarities with Python, being a dynamically typed scripting language. But it is still very far from the popularity that Python has in the field of data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little surprising, given its applications in areas that use quantitative methods, such as bioinformatics. When it comes to data science, Perl has several drawbacks: it won&amp;rsquo;t quickly become popular in the field, and its syntax is considered unfriendly. In addition, there are no attempts by its developers to create libraries that could be used in the field of data science. And as you and I know: often everything is decided by the right actions at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is a useful general-purpose scripting language, but it certainly won&amp;rsquo;t get you a data scientist job&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby is another dynamically typed general purpose interpreted language. However, it seems that its creators have no desire to make it suitable for data science jobs, as is the case with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem strange, but all of the above is in one way or another connected with the dominance of Python in the field of scientific research, as well as with the positive feedback from people who write in this language. The more people choose Python, the more modules and frameworks are developed for it, and the more programmers prefer Python. The SciRuby project was created to bring scientific computing functionality, such as matrix algebra, to Ruby. But, despite all these attempts, Python is still in the lead at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our verdict is not exactly the right choice for data science, but knowledge of Ruby will not hurt on your resume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, here we are with you and reviewed a short guide to programming languages ​​that come closest to the field of data science. The important point here is understanding what you need more: the specificity or universality of the language, its convenience or efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I regularly use R, Python and SQL as my current work is mainly focused on developing existing data pipelines and ETL processes. These languages ​​strike the right balance of generality and efficiency to get the job done, with the ability to use more advanced R statistical packages when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re already pretty good at Java, or you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to try Scala&amp;rsquo;s big data action, or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re crazy about the Julia project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you crammed MATLAB in class at the institute, or would you like to give SciRuby a chance to prove yourself? Yes, you can have hundreds of different reasons! If so, then leave your comment below - because it is really important for us to know the opinion of each of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thank-you-for-your-attention&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you for your attention!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 09.05.2022 - 15.05.2022 (Этап 4)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-week-09052022---15052022&#34;&gt;My week 09.05.2022 - 15.05.2022&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week started with a holiday. This is the day of victory. On this day, I had a fairly rich program. It was on this day that I returned to Moscow after a vacation. On the evening of May 9, there was a stunning solute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu6e87c2c510cc1d8701b1e07e118de19b_11689_23ff32988cd97aed524c68484d2cd598.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu6e87c2c510cc1d8701b1e07e118de19b_11689_f18cc6342e6da3ce3701279d3729b0e5.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu6e87c2c510cc1d8701b1e07e118de19b_11689_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/2_hu6e87c2c510cc1d8701b1e07e118de19b_11689_23ff32988cd97aed524c68484d2cd598.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;250&#34;
               height=&#34;250&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, after a week of rest, I started training. It was necessary to complete and hand over all the debts. I did two more OS labs in advance. On the OS, I learned to work with two editors vi and emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hu3471fac73aa742c0b3953b3fa3034252_166463_9f1650fc2fc2a9368644a071e5a24e2a.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hu3471fac73aa742c0b3953b3fa3034252_166463_4e1f7b37028a02d0d3b1f2fb84172be4.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hu3471fac73aa742c0b3953b3fa3034252_166463_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/3_hu3471fac73aa742c0b3953b3fa3034252_166463_9f1650fc2fc2a9368644a071e5a24e2a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;641&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also devoted a lot of time to French.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/1_hu564d71c140a870bcde8ba176f8141327_346121_00f0ea29c5075156db011cff814278a4.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/1_hu564d71c140a870bcde8ba176f8141327_346121_bec3e039053af2c65794dcb53a3a62d8.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/1_hu564d71c140a870bcde8ba176f8141327_346121_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/image/1_hu564d71c140a870bcde8ba176f8141327_346121_00f0ea29c5075156db011cff814278a4.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;507&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been quite productive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report in markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;report-in-markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report in markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theoretical introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completing of the work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; is a lightweight markup language that is a tool for converting code to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main feature of this language is the simplest syntax, which serves to simplify writing and reading markup code, which, in turn, makes it easy to correct it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the functions of the Markdown markup language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paragraphs and line breaks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headlines;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code blocks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontal (dividing) lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowercase elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text selection;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code fragments of strings;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;syntax-description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SYNTAX DESCRIPTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraphs-and-line-breaks&#34;&gt;Paragraphs and line breaks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create a paragraph using the syntax of the Markdown language, it is enough to separate the lines of text with one (or more) empty line (any line that contains nothing but spaces and tab characters is considered empty).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to insert a visible line break (the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element), you must end the line with two spaces and press the &amp;ldquo;Enter&amp;rdquo; key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many elements of the Markdown syntax look and work much better when they are formatted using &amp;ldquo;hard line translation&amp;rdquo; (line separation performed by the user himself, and not by the program automatically). Such elements include quotes, lists, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;headlines&#34;&gt;Headlines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown markup language supports 2 styles of heading designations: underlining and highlighting with a symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headings are highlighted using underscores with equal signs (&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;) if the title is of the first level, and hyphens (&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;) if the title is of the second level. The number of underscores is not limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When selecting headers using the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), from one to six of these characters are used, which are set at the beginning of the line (before the header). In this case, the number of characters corresponds to the header level. In addition, it is possible to provide the title with closing characters (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), although this is not mandatory. The number of closing characters does not have to match the number of initial characters. The level of the header is determined by the number of initial characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headings of the first and second levels, made using underscores, look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;First level header
========================
Second level header
-------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headings of the first, third and sixth levels, made using the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# First level header
### Third level header
###### Sixth level header
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above headings made with the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;) are identical to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# First level header #
### Third level header ###
###### Sixth level header ######
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-level-header&#34;&gt;Second level header&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header-1&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-level-header&#34;&gt;Third level header&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;sixth-level-header&#34;&gt;Sixth level header&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;quotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown language uses the &amp;ldquo;more&amp;rdquo; (&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;) sign to indicate quotations. It can be inserted both before each line of the quotation, and only before the first line of the paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the Markdown syntax allows you to create nested quotes (quotes inside quotes). Additional levels of citation marks (&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;) are used to mark them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes in Markdown can contain all kinds of markup elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes in the Markdown language look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;This is an example of a quote,
&amp;gt; in which an angle bracket is placed before each line.

&amp;gt;This is an example of a quote
in which the angle bracket
it is put only before the beginning of a new paragraph.
&amp;gt;The second paragraph.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedding a quote into a quote looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; First level of citation
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Second level of citation
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Third level of citation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example quote,
in which before each line
an angle bracket is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example of a quote
in which an angle bracket
is placed just before the beginning of a new paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enclosed quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second level of citation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third Citation Level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation Level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The citation level cannot exceed the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lists&#34;&gt;Lists&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports ordered (numbered) and unordered (unnumbered) lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markers such as asterisks, pluses and hyphens are used to form unordered lists. All the listed markers can be used interchangeably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To form ordered lists, numbers with a dot are used as markers. An important feature in this case is that the numbers themselves, with which the list is formed, are not important, since they do not affect the output HTML code. No matter how the user numbers the list, the output will in any case have an ordered list starting with one (1, 2, 3 &amp;hellip;). This feature should be taken into account when it is necessary to use the ordinal numbers of elements in the list so that they correspond to the numbers obtained in HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordered lists should always start with one. List markers usually start from the beginning of the line, however, they can be shifted, but not more than 3 spaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Explorer
2. Semiconductor
3. Dielectric
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unordered lists look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Explorer
* Semiconductor
* Dielectric
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Guide
- Semiconductor
- Dielectric
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+ Explorer
+ Semiconductor
+ Dielectric
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output of all three listed options has the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote inserted into the list looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. A list item with a quote:

    &amp;gt; This is a quote
    &amp;gt; inside the list item.

2. The second item of the list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list item with a quote:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quote
inside the list item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second item of the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When inserting quotes into the list items, it is important to keep in mind that the list items must be on the same level, and quotes must be indented. If the rule with a single list level is not followed, the next item in the list after the quote will be automatically numbered with the digit &amp;ldquo;1.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, if necessary, you can insert the source code into the list. In this case, it should be written with double indentation – 8 spaces or 2 tab characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list item containing the source code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;source code &amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;code-blocks&#34;&gt;Code Blocks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formatted code blocks are used when it is necessary to quote the source code of programs or markup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a block of code in the Markdown language, it is necessary to start each line of a paragraph with an indent consisting of four spaces or one tab character. The code block continues until there is a line without indentation (or the end of the text). Inside the code block, ampersands (&amp;quot;&amp;amp;&amp;quot;) and angle brackets (&amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;quot; and &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo;) are automatically converted into HTML markup elements. In addition, it should be noted that inside the code blocks, the usual Markdown syntax is not processed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code block in Markdown looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a regular paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is a block of code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;horizontal-lines-separators&#34;&gt;Horizontal lines (separators)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create a horizontal line using the Markdown syntax, you need to place three (or more)a hyphen or asterisk on a separate line of text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to place spaces between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontal lines in Markdown look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The first part of the text to be divided
***
The second part of the text that needs to be divided
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The first part of the text to be divided
---
The second part of the text that needs to be divided
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the text to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the text that needs to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using this tool, it is important to remember that an empty line must be left after the first part of the text and before the second. This rule must be observed only when using hyphens. If it is not followed, the second-level header and a line of plain text will be displayed on the screen. When using the asterisk symbol, this rule can be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lowercase-elements&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowercase elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports two styles of link design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperlink, with immediate indication of the address (in-text);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hyperlink similar to a footnote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is assumed that in addition to the URL, there is also a link text. It is enclosed in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create an in-text hyperlink, you must use parentheses immediately after the closing square one. You need to put a URL inside them. It is also possible to place the name enclosed in quotation marks in them, which will be displayed when hovering, but this item is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  [example](http://example.com / &amp;quot;Optional hint&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen: [example](&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://example.com&lt;/a&gt; / &amp;ldquo;Optional hint&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When referring to a local directory, it is possible to use a relative path (from the current page, site, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating a passable hyperlink, a second pair of square brackets is used instead of the target address, inside which the label, the link identifier (id) is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[example][id]:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, you can use a space to separate 2 pairs of square brackets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[example] [id]: 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, it is possible to determine the identifier anywhere in the document.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: http://example.com / &amp;quot;Optional hint&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[example] [id]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://example.com&lt;/a&gt; / &amp;ldquo;Optional hint&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, it consists of the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link ID surrounded by square brackets (which may be preceded by an optional indentation from one to three spaces);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colon;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or more spaces (or tab characters);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperlink URL;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optional title (a hint to the image that pops up when you hover over it) of the hyperlink, enclosed either in double or single quotes, or in parentheses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link identifiers can consist of letters, numbers, spaces, and punctuation marks, but they are not case sensitive. That is, these two options are equivalent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link text][a]
[link text][A]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown also allows you to use an implicitly expressed identifier (abbreviated). In this case, the label is not given, instead the hyperlink text is used as its name, and the second pair of square brackets remains empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to make the word &amp;ldquo;Example&amp;rdquo; a hyperlink leading to the site &amp;lt;http://example.com /&amp;gt;, it is enough to write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Example][]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then define the hyperlink:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Example]: http://example.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:
[Example][]
[Example]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://example.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;text-selection&#34;&gt;Text selection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown perceives asterisks &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo; and underscores &amp;ldquo;_&amp;rdquo; as signs of semantic text selection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text surrounded by single &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;_&amp;rdquo; will be enclosed in the HTML tag &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text surrounded by double &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;_&amp;rdquo; will be enclosed in the HTML tag &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, text surrounded by single characters is highlighted in italics, and text surrounded by double characters is highlighted in bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the selected fragment can be located in any part of the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text in italics using the Markdown syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;*Example* 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text in bold using the Markdown syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;**Example**
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text in italics in bold using the Markdown syntax looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;***Example***
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the above examples are similar to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;_example_

__example__

Re___distribution___division

___example___
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;code-fragments-of-strings&#34;&gt;Code fragments of strings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark a line fragment containing the code, it is necessary to surround it with reverse apostrophes &amp;ldquo;`&amp;rdquo;. When using code fragments of strings, the text will be displayed as a monospaced font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike code blocks, a code fragment allows you to put the code inside a regular paragraph of text.
The code fragment of a string in the Markdown language looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; operator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 ways to insert images into a document in Markdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. By directly specifying the URL of the image. The syntax of this command is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Alternative text](/path/to/image.jpg)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Alternative text](/path/to/image.jpg &amp;quot;Hint&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, it consists of the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;exclamation mark;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;square brackets, which indicate the text alternative to the image (it will become the content of the attribute in the img element);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;parentheses containing the URL or relative path of the image, as well as (optionally) a tooltip enclosed in double or single quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Using an identifier label. The syntax of this command is written as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Alternative text][id]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &amp;ldquo;id&amp;rdquo; is the name of a specific image label. Image labels are defined using a syntax that is completely identical to hyperlink labels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[id]: path/to/image &amp;quot;Optional hint&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important feature is that Markdown does not allow you to set image dimensions (width, height).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using a plain-text editor. John Gruber and Aaron Swartz created Markdown in 2004 as a markup language that is appealing to human readers in its source code form. Markdown is widely used in blogging, instant messaging, online forums, collaborative software, documentation pages, and readme files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial description of Markdown contained ambiguities and raised unanswered questions, causing implementations to both intentionally and accidentally diverge from the original version. This was addressed in 2014, when long-standing Markdown contributors released CommonMark, an unambiguous specification and test suite for Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n 2002 Aaron Swartz created atx, &amp;ldquo;the true structured text format&amp;rdquo;. Swartz and Gruber then worked together to create the Markdown language in 2004, with the goal of enabling people &amp;ldquo;to write using an easy-to-read and easy-to-write plain text format, optionally convert it to structurally valid XHTML (or HTML)&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its key design goal was readability, that the language be readable as-is, without looking like it has been marked up with tags or formatting instructions, unlike text formatted with a markup language, such as Rich Text Format (RTF) or HTML, which have obvious tags and formatting instructions. To this end, its main inspiration is the existing conventions for marking up plain text in email, though it also draws from earlier markup languages, notably setext, Textile, and reStructuredText.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gruber wrote a Perl script, Markdown.pl, which converts marked-up text input to valid, well-formed XHTML or HTML and replaces angle brackets (&amp;lt;, &amp;gt;) and ampersands (&amp;amp;) with their corresponding character entity references. It can take the role of a standalone script, a plugin for Blosxom or a Movable Type, or of a text filter for BBEdit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-and-divergence&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rise and divergence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Markdown&amp;rsquo;s popularity grew rapidly, many Markdown implementations appeared, driven mostly by the need for additional features such as tables, footnotes, definition lists, and Markdown inside HTML blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The behavior of some of these diverged from the reference implementation, as Markdown was only characterised by an informal specification and a Perl implementation for conversion to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a number of ambiguities in the informal specification had attracted attention. These issues spurred the creation of tools such as Babelmark to compare the output of various implementations, and an effort by some developers of Markdown parsers for standardisation. However, Gruber has argued that complete standardization would be a mistake: &amp;ldquo;Different sites (and people) have different needs. No one syntax would make all happy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standardization&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standardization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2012, a group of people, including Jeff Atwood and John MacFarlane, launched what Atwood characterised as a standardisation effort. A community website now aims to &amp;ldquo;document various tools and resources available to document authors and developers, as well as implementors of the various Markdown implementations&amp;rdquo;. In September 2014, Gruber objected to the usage of &amp;ldquo;Markdown&amp;rdquo; in the name of this effort and it was rebranded as CommonMark. CommonMark.org published several versions of a specification, reference implementation, test suite, and &amp;quot; to announce a finalized 1.0 spec and test suite in 2019.&amp;quot; No 1.0 spec has since been released as major issues still remain unsolved. Nonetheless, the following sites and projects have adopted CommonMark: Discourse, GitHub, GitLab, Reddit, Qt, Stack Exchange (Stack Overflow), and Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2016 two relevant informational Internet RFCs were published:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RFC 7763 introduced MIME type &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;text/markdown.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RFC 7764 discussed and registered the variants MultiMarkdown, GitHub Flavored Markdown (GFM), Pandoc, and Markdown Extra among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementations&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementations of Markdown are available for over a dozen programming languages; in addition, many platforms and frameworks support Markdown. For example, Markdown plugins exist for every major blogging platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Markdown is a minimal markup language and is read and edited with a normal text editor, there are specially designed editors that preview the files with styles, which are available for all major platforms. Many general purpose text and code editors have syntax highlighting plugins for Markdown built into them or available as optional download. Editors may feature a side-by-side preview window or render the code directly in a WYSIWYG fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;JotterPad&lt;/em&gt; – an online WYSIWYG editor that supports Markdown and fountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doxygen&lt;/em&gt; – a source code documentation generator which supports Markdown with extra features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RStudio&lt;/em&gt; – an IDE for R. It provides a C++ wrapper function for a markdown variant called sundown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Flavored Markdown (GFM) ignores underscores in words, and adds syntax highlighting, task lists, and tables RMarkdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nextcloud Notes&lt;/em&gt; - the default app for taking notes on the Nextcloud platform supports formatting using Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 2.05.2022 - 8.05.2022 (Этап 3)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I went home, rested with my family. In my free time, I was engaged in self-development, as I did laboratory work in advance. I have read Unix literature. Had a lot of fun with my best friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this week has passed by 100%. I had a very good rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu82fe5bf69b402c4322cc549e8ac8fbc2_27060_0f05c4d3ed0fce551ff318cfde2c3d0d.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu82fe5bf69b402c4322cc549e8ac8fbc2_27060_1b87acab4ec3ee7d374137f5f68980fa.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu82fe5bf69b402c4322cc549e8ac8fbc2_27060_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/images/1_hu82fe5bf69b402c4322cc549e8ac8fbc2_27060_0f05c4d3ed0fce551ff318cfde2c3d0d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;600&#34;
               height=&#34;400&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is a software for tracking changes in any set of files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers collaboratively developing source code during software development. Its goals include speed, data integrity, and support for distributed, non-linear workflows (thousands of parallel branches running on different systems).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git development began in April 2005, after many developers of the Linux kernel gave up access to BitKeeper, a proprietary source-control management (SCM) system that they had been using to maintain the project since 2002. The copyright holder of BitKeeper, Larry McVoy, had withdrawn free use of the product after claiming that Andrew Tridgell had created SourcePuller by reverse engineering the BitKeeper protocols. The same incident also spurred the creation of another version-control system, Mercurial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus Torvalds wanted a distributed system that he could use like BitKeeper, but none of the available free systems met his needs.  Torvalds cited an example of a source-control management system needing 30 seconds to apply a patch and update all associated metadata, and noted that this would not scale to the needs of Linux kernel development, where synchronizing with fellow maintainers could require 250 such actions at once. For his design criterion, he specified that patching should take no more than three seconds, and added three more goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Concurrent Versions System (CVS) as an example of what not to do; if in doubt, make the exact opposite decision.
Support a distributed, BitKeeper-like workflow.
Include very strong safeguards against corruption, either accidental or malicious.
These criteria eliminated every version-control system in use at the time, so immediately after the 2.6.12-rc2 Linux kernel development release, Torvalds set out to write his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of Git began on 3 April 2005. Torvalds announced the project on 6 April and became self-hosting the next day. The first merge of multiple branches took place on 18 April. Torvalds achieved his performance goals; on 29 April, the nascent Git was benchmarked recording patches to the Linux kernel tree at the rate of 6.7 patches per second. On 16 June, Git managed the kernel 2.6.12 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torvalds turned over maintenance on 26 July 2005 to Junio Hamano, a major contributor to the project. Hamano was responsible for the 1.0 release on 21 December 2005 and remains the project&amp;rsquo;s core maintainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git&amp;rsquo;s design was inspired by BitKeeper and Monotone. Git was originally designed as a low-level version-control system engine, on top of which others could write front ends, such as Cogito or StGIT. The core Git project has since become a complete version-control system that is usable directly. While strongly influenced by BitKeeper, Torvalds deliberately avoided conventional approaches, leading to a unique design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementations&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git (the main implementation in C) is primarily developed on Linux, although it also supports most major operating systems, including the BSDs (DragonFly BSD, FreeBSD, NetBSD, and OpenBSD), Solaris, macOS, and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Windows port of Git was primarily a Linux-emulation framework that hosts the Linux version. Installing Git under Windows creates a similarly named Program Files directory containing the Mingw-w64 port of the GNU Compiler Collection, Perl 5, MSYS2 (itself a fork of Cygwin, a Unix-like emulation environment for Windows) and various other Windows ports or emulations of Linux utilities and libraries. Currently, native Windows builds of Git are distributed as 32- and 64-bit installers. The git official website currently maintains a build of Git for Windows, still using the MSYS2 environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JGit implementation of Git is a pure Java software library, designed to be embedded in any Java application. JGit is used in the Gerrit code-review tool, and in EGit, a Git client for the Eclipse IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go-git is an open-source implementation of Git written in pure Go. It is currently used for backing projects as a SQL interface for Git code repositories and providing encryption for Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dulwich implementation of Git is a pure Python software component for Python 2.7, 3.4 and 3.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The libgit2 implementation of Git is an ANSI C software library with no other dependencies, which can be built on multiple platforms, including Windows, Linux, macOS, and BSD. It has bindings for many programming languages, including Ruby, Python, and Haskell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JS-Git is a JavaScript implementation of a subset of Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git does not provide access-control mechanisms, but was designed for operation with other tools that specialize in access control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 17 December 2014, an exploit was found affecting the Windows and macOS versions of the Git client. An attacker could perform arbitrary code execution on a target computer with Git installed by creating a malicious Git tree (directory) named .git (a directory in Git repositories that stores all the data of the repository) in a different case (such as .GIT or .Git, needed because Git does not allow the all-lowercase version of .git to be created manually) with malicious files in the .git/hooks subdirectory (a folder with executable files that Git runs) on a repository that the attacker made or on a repository that the attacker can modify. If a Windows or Mac user pulls (downloads) a version of the repository with the malicious directory, then switches to that directory, the .git directory will be overwritten (due to the case-insensitive trait of the Windows and Mac filesystems) and the malicious executable files in .git/hooks may be run, which results in the attacker&amp;rsquo;s commands being executed. An attacker could also modify the .git/config configuration file, which allows the attacker to create malicious Git aliases (aliases for Git commands or external commands) or modify extant aliases to execute malicious commands when run. The vulnerability was patched in version 2.2.1 of Git, released on 17 December 2014, and announced the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git version 2.6.1, released on 29 September 2015, contained a patch for a security vulnerability (CVE-2015-7545) that allowed arbitrary code execution. The vulnerability was exploitable if an attacker could convince a victim to clone a specific URL, as the arbitrary commands were embedded in the URL itself. An attacker could use the exploit via a man-in-the-middle attack if the connection was unencrypted, as they could redirect the user to a URL of their choice. Recursive clones were also vulnerable, since they allowed the controller of a repository to specify arbitrary URLs via the gitmodules file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git uses SHA-1 hashes internally. Linus Torvalds has responded that the hash was mostly to guard against accidental corruption, and the security a cryptographically secure hash gives was just an accidental side effect, with the main security being signing elsewhere. Since a demonstration of the SHAttered attack against git in 2017, git was modified to use a SHA-1 variant resistant to this attack. A plan for hash function transition is being written since February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
